<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport</id>
    <title>MDD OC Blog</title>
    <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport"/>
    <subtitle>MDD OC Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/img/logo.svg</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDD advice rapport 2023-2024]]></title>
        <id>https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024</id>
        <link href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024"/>
        <updated>2024-11-03T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>The OC started to become more transparent in what they do and how they do it. We hope this will give the students a better understanding and trust in the way the members represent them.</p>
<p>This year we saw the normalization for the use of AI in the workplace. Although the Master Digital Design (MDD) embraces new technologies, as reflected last year, we are aware that we should remain critical in its' use. Concerns were raised from the teaching staff as there was a significant increase in LLM generated text in student documents submitted for assessments.</p>
<p>The MDD started an open discussion with this years' cohort on what are the expectations and how can we, together, use AI in a responsible matter. We hope to continue this discussion with the next cohort.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="composition-and-appointment-of-the-program-committee">Composition and appointment of the program committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#composition-and-appointment-of-the-program-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Composition and appointment of the program committee" title="Direct link to Composition and appointment of the program committee">​</a></h2>
<p>The two student representatives have been selected by the whole cohort during an in-class election. Out of 4 candidates, 2 students were selected by popular vote.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th>Name members</th><th>Staff or Student</th><th>Member since</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Karim Marei</td><td>Student</td><td>2023</td></tr><tr><td>Eli Keshavarzikhoozani</td><td>Student</td><td>2023</td></tr><tr><td>Sander Boer</td><td>Staff</td><td>2021</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3"><p>Chairman’s name: Sander Boer</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="education-committee">Education committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#education-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Education committee" title="Direct link to Education committee">​</a></h2>
<p>The table below shows how many members have completed or are in the process of completing HvA OC training.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th></th><th>Number of members</th><th>Number completed</th><th>Number in progress</th></tr><tr><th colspan="2"></th><th>OC education HvA</th><th>OC education HvA</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Education Committee</td><td>3</td><td>2</td><td>1</td></tr></tbody></table>
<p>It is important to note that, due to unfortunate planning of the chair, this years advice report has not been reviewd by the student members.</p>
<p>As will be mentioned in the intentions for upcoming academic year, the OC is striving to become a more mature body within the MDD.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="facilitate-program-committee-and-testing-committee">Facilitate program committee and testing committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#facilitate-program-committee-and-testing-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Facilitate program committee and testing committee" title="Direct link to Facilitate program committee and testing committee">​</a></h2>
<table><thead><tr><th colspan="2">Facilitate members of training committee</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Does the number of hours made available to the program committee at least meet the HvA-wide lower limit set: (80)</td><td><strong>yes</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Are additional hours - beyond the lower limit - provided to the training committee?</td><td><strong>no</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Does the program committee have administrative support (official secretary) </td><td><strong>no</strong></td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evaluation-on-the-education-and-examination-regulations-oer">Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#evaluation-on-the-education-and-examination-regulations-oer" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)" title="Direct link to Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Describe - briefly and in summary - the main points of the opinion on the OER.</strong></p>
<p>Since the introduction of the <code>no grades</code> system in the MDD concerns have been raised for potential further positions beyond the program. Some positions require a specific GPA. While the MDD provides a translation table from <code>no grade</code> to <code>grade</code> when required, it is impossible to even reach a <em>summa cum laude</em>. Only when receiving the max "grade" (<code>Visionary</code>) on all indicators, which is highly unlikely, you are eligible to receive this distinction on your diploma. Similarly for <em>cum laude</em>, reaching a 8.0, is a near-impossible achievement. The advice from the OC is to (re-)adjust the translation matrix to make it possible for students to graduate with distinction.</p>
<p><strong>Indicate whether, in the opinion of the program committee, its recommendations on the OER are generally taken seriously.</strong></p>
<p>Although most concerns were taken seriously, the limitations on changing the OER was noted by the OC. One of the biggest concerns for this years OC was the sudden change of hearts into a <code>no grades</code> system while the details of this needs to be worked out more before it could be generally accepted to work in the benefit of the students.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evaluation-on-the-use-of-study-advance-funds-svm">Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#evaluation-on-the-use-of-study-advance-funds-svm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)" title="Direct link to Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>In what way is the training committee involved in the development of plans for the spending of SVM the decision-making on them?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><strong>In what way is the training committee informed about the realization of the plans?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><strong>Describe what the training committee thinks about:</strong></p>
<p><em>“the involvement of the program committee in the development of plans for the spending of SVM and its decision-making (full discussion partner, timely involvement, plans submitted for approval?)“</em></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><em>”the information that the program committee receives about the realization of the plans (sufficiently clear and at the agreed upon times?)”</em></p>
<p>// TODO</p>
<p><strong>Describe what the program committee thinks about the realization of the plans: in the opinion of the program committee, have the plans been realized to a sufficient degree or not?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advice-and-evaluation-on-advice-to-management">Advice and evaluation on advice to management<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#advice-and-evaluation-on-advice-to-management" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advice and evaluation on advice to management" title="Direct link to Advice and evaluation on advice to management">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Describe - briefly and in summary - the main points of the other advice (i.e., not about the OER and the spending of SVM) issued by the program committees.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The <code>dojos</code> and <code>masterclasses</code> provided during the year were received as very useful. The OC would like to note that it would be beneficial to the program to structure these events more so that students can plan around this.</li>
<li>Reflecting on the <code>Foundations</code> weeks, the OC noted that this took a significant chunk of the academic year. While they are perceived as useful, which differs per foundation/student, it would be good to reconsider the foundation-weeks. The OC proposed to the staff to think about a way in which foundations could be given in parallel to both reduce the time-period on which they need to take place as well as the option for students to pick foundations they would like to take part in (e.g. not taking part in a typography foundation with a background as a professional UI designer)</li>
<li>The MDD staff has been lacking clear communication over the course of the past year. This resulted in students not knowing what was going on in the program and made it hard to plan accordingly. While efforts were made during the year to provide a planning at least a week ahead, the OC thinks this is a big area of improvement for coming academic years.</li>
<li>The MDD makes a distinction between formative and summative assessments. While the latter is the official moment to received a grade the OC advices the MDD to give an indication on where the student stands in the formative assessment besides the provided written feedback.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Examples of subjects on which the program committee can advise innovations in education; the self-reflection drawn up by the program during an accreditation or midterm; the way in which education is evaluated; etc.</strong></p>
<p>The OC feels like it can help steer/guide the conversation on the use of AI/LLM technology in the work of the students. What is unclear as of now is how the MDD will uphold the rules and regulations of the HvA when it comes to the use of AI/LLM technology in the work of the students where it is also promoted to experiment with new technologies.</p>
<p><strong>Indicate whether, in the opinion of the program committee, the advice is generally taken seriously.</strong></p>
<p>Although most concerns were taken seriously, the limitations on changing the OER was noted by the OC. One of the biggest concerns for this years OC was the sudden change of hearts into a <code>no grades</code> system while the details of this needs to be worked out more before it could be generally accepted to work in the benefit of the students.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="intentions-for-upcoming-academic-year">Intentions for upcoming academic year<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2023-2024#intentions-for-upcoming-academic-year" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Intentions for upcoming academic year" title="Direct link to Intentions for upcoming academic year">​</a></h2>
<p>While we are a small program and the OC is in continuous rotation of its' members we would like to give the OC more structure and shape.</p>
<p>By providing a more mature OC we can be a stronger voice for the students and help guide the future growth MDD, respecting the needs of the program as well as those of the (future) students.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Eli Keshavarzikhoozani</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Karim Marei</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Sander Boer</name>
            <uri>mailto:a.s.boer@hva.nl</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MDD advice rapport 2022-2023]]></title>
        <id>https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023</id>
        <link href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023"/>
        <updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="introduction">Introduction<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#introduction" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Introduction" title="Direct link to Introduction">​</a></h2>
<p>This year has been marked by transformative changes, both within the program as well as within the design field as a whole. The Dutch government announced changes to the management of international students and new financial regulations to the admissions process were added. As a result, international students were somewhat less than in previous years.</p>
<p>In 2022, MDD welcomed new leadership to the program, injecting fresh ideas and perspectives. With renewed direction and enthusiasm, this year was a year of restructuring and trying out new ideas for the curriculum, such as the introduction of a project ‘Afterlife’. These changes were met with challenges due to understaffing, but nevertheless the staff did their best to navigate these hurdles.</p>
<p>New AI technologies, such as ChatGPT, took the world by storm. These new technologies opened new avenues for teaching, research and writing, and we welcomed ways these new technologies could be used by both students and teachers.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="composition-and-appointment-of-the-program-committee">Composition and appointment of the program committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#composition-and-appointment-of-the-program-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Composition and appointment of the program committee" title="Direct link to Composition and appointment of the program committee">​</a></h2>
<table><thead><tr><th>Name members</th><th>Teacher or Student</th><th>Member since</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Romar van Tongeren</td><td>Student</td><td>2022</td></tr><tr><td>Sander Boer</td><td>Teacher</td><td>2021</td></tr><tr><td>Sjoerd Simmerman</td><td>Student</td><td>2022</td></tr><tr><td>Yaşmine Khalil</td><td>Student</td><td>2022</td></tr><tr><td colspan="3"><p>Chairman’s name: Sander Boer</p></td></tr></tbody></table>
<table><thead><tr><th colspan="2">Information</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>1.</td><td>All students and teacher are from the progam Master Digital Design</td></tr><tr><td>2.</td><td>The participants are multicultural, reflecting MDD</td></tr><tr><td>3.</td><td>To decide on members of the OC, students volunteered, then a selection of three students was made from around 8 volunteers.</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="education-committee">Education committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#education-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Education committee" title="Direct link to Education committee">​</a></h2>
<p>The table below shows how many members have completed or are in the process of completing HvA OC training.</p>
<table><thead><tr><th></th><th>Number of members</th><th>Number completed</th><th>Number in progress</th></tr><tr><th colspan="2"></th><th>OC education HvA</th><th>OC education HvA</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Education Committee</td><td>4</td><td>0</td><td>0</td></tr></tbody></table>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="facilitate-program-committee-and-testing-committee">Facilitate program committee and testing committee<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#facilitate-program-committee-and-testing-committee" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Facilitate program committee and testing committee" title="Direct link to Facilitate program committee and testing committee">​</a></h2>
<table><thead><tr><th colspan="2">Facilitate members of training committee</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Does the number of hours made available to the program committee at least meet the HvA-wide lower limit set: (80)</td><td><strong>yes</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Are additional hours - beyond the lower limit - provided to the training committee?</td><td><strong>no</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Does the program committee have administrative support (official secretary) </td><td><strong>no</strong></td></tr></tbody></table>
<ul>
<li>Lower limit of hours was split amongst 3 OC members, not including the chairman</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evaluation-on-the-education-and-examination-regulations-oer">Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#evaluation-on-the-education-and-examination-regulations-oer" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)" title="Direct link to Evaluation on the Education and Examination Regulations (OER)">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Describe - briefly and in summary - the main points of the opinion on the OER.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>We noticed vague usage of terms which are confusing with the indicators that have been examined with. We learned that the terms were just outdated and not used anymore.</li>
<li>Outdated writing within the OER in regard to the updated competencies that are used for official assessments.</li>
<li>We learned a lot of structural changes could not be made due to the limitations of accreditation.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Indicate whether, in the opinion of the program committee, its recommendations on the OER are generally taken seriously.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Recommendations to the OER were generally taken seriously, however they were not implemented sufficiently. Not many changes were made to the official OER this year because of limited room for adjustment and insufficient time to be able to make meaningful changes.</li>
<li>The education committee strongly recommends looking at the feedback received from the OC during this education year, during the next educational year. Since the feedback is not properly applied to the completed OER document of 2023/2024, due to the previously listed reasons.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="evaluation-on-the-use-of-study-advance-funds-svm">Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#evaluation-on-the-use-of-study-advance-funds-svm" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)" title="Direct link to Evaluation on the use of study advance funds (SVM)">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>In what way is the training committee involved in the development of plans for the spending of SVM the decision-making on them?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><strong>In what way is the training committee informed about the realization of the plans?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><strong>Describe what the training committee thinks about:</strong></p>
<p><em>“the involvement of the program committee in the development of plans for the spending of SVM and its decision-making (full discussion partner, timely involvement, plans submitted for approval?)“</em></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<p><em>”the information that the program committee receives about the realization of the plans (sufficiently clear and at the agreed upon times?)”</em></p>
<p>Most plans are scheduled for next year. So, validation is still needed. They verbally took our feedback seriously but through the documentation, we feel like not everything is looked at with the same value.</p>
<p><strong>Describe what the program committee thinks about the realization of the plans: in the opinion of the program committee, have the plans been realized to a sufficient degree or not?</strong></p>
<p>None, the OC was not involved in the SVM.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="advice-and-evaluation-on-advice-to-management">Advice and evaluation on advice to management<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#advice-and-evaluation-on-advice-to-management" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Advice and evaluation on advice to management" title="Direct link to Advice and evaluation on advice to management">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>Describe - briefly and in summary - the main points of the other advice (i.e., not about the OER and the spending of SVM) issued by the program committees.</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Plagiarism in context to group work and ways to claim credits (ChatGPT &amp; Group work)</li>
<li>Mandatory participation and how attendance is measured
-Rewriting 8.1 text explaining the 5 competencies of MDD’s assessment</li>
<li>Discussed “behavioral assessment” in context with written reflection (3.1.1).</li>
<li>Generally confusing terminology</li>
</ul>
<p>The writers of the MDD OER asked us to read their document of the OER and give feedback to any parts that we might have something to say about. All given feedback was discussed prehend and handed to the writers of the MDD OER.</p>
<p><strong>Examples of subjects on which the program committee can advise innovations in education; the self-reflection drawn up by the program during an accreditation or midterm; the way in which education is evaluated; etc.</strong></p>
<p>Students have expressed comments that written reflections are not the best way to assess their work as designers. We wanted to ideate on how to better assess students during midterm and finals but were limited by school regulations. We also suggested better planning ahead for classes and other logistics, as students felt that announcements were last minute or not planned properly. For example, final assessment dates were announced about 3 weeks in advance.</p>
<p><strong>Indicate whether, in the opinion of the program committee, the advice is generally taken seriously.</strong></p>
<p>As mentioned before, during meetings with the writers of the OER we felt open to discussing our feedback on the form. However, after this year we do not see some parts adjusted the way we envisioned it. We believe this is mostly because of a lack of time on the writing side, which they expressed during our meeting.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="intentions-for-upcoming-academic-year">Intentions for upcoming academic year<a href="https://xiduzo.github.io/mdd-oc/rapport/2022-2023#intentions-for-upcoming-academic-year" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Intentions for upcoming academic year" title="Direct link to Intentions for upcoming academic year">​</a></h2>
<p><strong>What topics does the education committee want to take up.</strong></p>
<p>As students we were asked to give feedback on the method of assessment and parts about where classes do fit in the year. As the OC we believe it would help to present a written document about the following year to show the results of these discussions.<br>
<!-- -->To get more out of the OC we would have liked to attend discussions about the plans for next year. This includes early setup of a new OC since the master is only one year and they have to find new participants every year.</p>
<p>We also believe that OC orientated forms are made in Dutch which is difficult to work with since our education is international. We believe the HvA should be more inclusive in this way.</p>
<p><strong><em>Explanation</em></strong></p>
<p>The HvA attaches great importance to the proper functioning of the program committee. On the basis of the annual report, the program committee briefly describes its activities in the past academic year and offers pointers for the OC in the coming academic year.</p>
<p>The annual report is presented to the program manager, the dean and the Faculty Council. The annual report of the program committee must be submitted by October 1.</p>
<p>The annual report of the OC must be published on the program's website.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Romar van Tongeren</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Sander Boer</name>
            <uri>mailto:a.s.boer@hva.nl</uri>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Sjoerd Simmerman</name>
        </author>
        <author>
            <name>Yasmine Khalil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>